

Shashank Reddy Sunkara

Date of birth: 5 Apr 1994

Nationality: Indian

Gender: Male

CONTACT

• 1-9-1296/4, Deendayal Nagar, Hunter Hills, Hanamkonda 506001 Warangal, India



(+91) 8121755566

https:// shashankreddysunkara.githu b.io/CV/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/reddy-s/

Skype: live:sunkaras58



ABOUT ME

Dedicated and focused IT Technical Professional of overall 3+ years of experience who excels at prioritizing and completing multiple and complex tasks simultaneously. Specialized as SRE, DevOps Engineer, DevOps Team Lead managing production and lower environments and all critical and non-critical applications. Committed to delivering high-quality results by being energetic, organized, and professional.

WORK EXPERIENCE

15 OCT 2020 - CURRENT - Gurgaon, India

Senior DevOps Engineer / DevOps Team Lead & Manager

Datacultr Pvt. Ltd.

- **Lead** the **DevOps Team** of 3 people.
- Took lead in Azure to AWS migration tasks by using migration tools & also manual way and successfully migrated in 3 weeks by reducing VMs footprint from 75 to 31 by optimizing the usage.
- Set up ALB, EIP, NAT, EC2, S3, Advanced monitoring on services, cloud watch, RDS, beanstalk, Migration services, SG, VPC, IAM, Cloud front, X-Ray, Cloud Formation, Kinesis, AWS Cost explorer, Budget and Billing, Auto-scaling and alerts.
- Created multiple dashboards for AWS services, Servers metri cs in Grafana with dynamic selection of parameters.
- Installed Prometheus, Node exporter, blackbox exporter, cad visor in a docker-compose format in all production, staging, a nd testing servers with persistence storage.
- Gathered user requirements from multiple teams like the dev team and L1-support team to craft efficient monitoring, alarm ing solutions, and dashboards in grafana, Zabbix, and in kiba na.
- Tracked down and eradicated the attackers' virus (bit mining viruses that utilize 100% of CPU resources and cause full load), unauthorized keys, phantom scripts, and so forth securities that compromised in backend and database servers.
- Modified Nginx configuration to block unauthorized hits in endpoints by use of error blocks and fail2ban.
- Architect, design, develop, deploy, and maintain the enterprise logging platform using **ELK**.
- Configured Filebeat to trace specific file paths on your host and use Logstash (ELK Stack) as the destination endpoint.
- Cognizance on different agents like log files (Filebeat), network metrics (Packetbeat), and server metrics (Metricbeat).
- Configured 3 nodes set up for Elasticsearch, Logstash, and Kib ana stack
- Support the development team with front-end visualization dashboards using kibana.
- Created **nginx kibana** dashboard to show a number of HTTPS hits from clients and categories of **200,404,400 and 500** HTTP response codes in numbers.
- Worked on **Sentry** application performance monitoring (**APM**) tool to debug issues in **transactions** via applications, and backend servers, etc.
- Manages environments requests and environment allocation to project teams.
- Own the Production, Staging, and Development infrastructures.
- Design, manage, test, document, automate, deploy, secure, monitor, scale, descale, support, and sustain the 24/7 Bare Metal, Amazon EC2, Azure private cloud architectures.

- Day-to-day support for applications hosted on Azure or other Cloud providers like AWS.
- System administration in support of Linux, Nginx, MongoDB,
 Django, Python, Kafka, Elastic, and Go.
- Setup and manage the end-to-end CI/CD pipeline with Jenkins f or Production and staging environments.
- Merge test and staging applications into their designated specified single-stage and test VM respectively to reduce VM footprint and cost in the Azure and AWS infra cloud.

Financial and insurance activities

27 JUN 2019 - 29 MAR 2020 - McLean, United States

DevOps Engineer

Freddie Mac Corp.

- Managed health of the environments to be green and proactively coordinated as well as resolved the environment downtime-related issues.
- Initiated and tracked the environment build-out requests for traditional as well as new technologies like **Docker**, **Open Shift**, and **Cloud**, etc.
- Worked on APM tool App Dynamics to get a stack trace, bread crumbs on transactions with a duration of execution or processing time, and provide RCA to Lead and manager of the project at production level.
- Created **Grafana alerting** setup by use of alerting feature that can communicate with **dev** and **L-1 support teams** through **Sla**
- Configured CloudWatch, Prometheus, influx DB datasources in grafana.
- Installed **worldping** plugin in grafana to get **ping**, **ICMP** checks on URLs of applications.
- Architect, design, develop, deploy, and maintained the enter prise logging platform using ELK.
- Configured dashboards to monitor multiple containers, serve rs, URLs, network, and RDS in Grafana.
- Contributed to design understanding the architectural tradeoffs including Scalability, Resiliency, High Availability and Securit y.
- Performed capacity planning and solution review related to the ELK environment.
- Worked with data log streaming platforms and tools to ingest data from systems, applications, and access logs.
- Designed and built multi-tenant dashboard solutions in Kibana and Grafana.
- Optimized and tuned the ELK environment (File beat, logstash) to meet the performance requirements.
- Hands-on experience with supporting Elasticsearch in producti on, handling medium to large clusters.
- Experienced in setting up ELK Stack (Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana stack) to process data from multiple data sources
- Experienced with Kibana visualization strategies, controls, and techniques
- Experienced with Elasticsearch index configuration options, sha rding, aliases, etc.
- Troubleshot lower environments like **Dev & cert** and higher environments like **UAT, Maint, Perf & Prod,** and application issues.
- Ensured Non-Prod environments stability and availability.
- Worked on ELK to view logs and created dashboards for the graphical representation of metrics.
- Supported New production environment build-out and deployment.
- $\,^\circ\,$ Maintained and Managed software version modification of project ecosystem.

- Developed and maintained a CI/CD pipeline and ansible scripts.
- Applied experience of **DevOps/SCM** best practices to enable highly available & reliable systems.
- Took full end-to-end ownership of certain elements/business processes/capabilities within the **Atlassian** suite.
- Vetted new Atlassian feature ideas, configurations, etc.
- Maintained up-to-date knowledge of the Atlassian products, process best practices, and obtain and maintain certification with the various Atlassian products.
- Maintained Atlassian tools in both Unix and Windows environm ents. Performs end-user activities in the Atlassian tools, such as creating workflows in JIRA, authored content in Confluence, creating build plans in Bamboo, etc.,

14 APR 2018 - 27 MAY 2019 - Moline, United States

IT Technical Analyst IV

Deere & Company Corp. WHQ

- Involved myself in discussions related to application production issues with Architects, tech leads, infrastructure analysts, business analysts, and developers.
- Proficiently served my cloud foundry skills to resolve timeout issues, blue-green deployments in testing and production en vironments.
- Created docker-compose files with services like Grafana, Prome theus, node exporter, and black-box exporter.
- Managed monitoring services installed like Grafana, Promethe us in ubuntu servers with CPU, RAM, IOPS, and throughputs f or better performance.
- Delivered effective technical support (application, software, and operations) in all environments for a critical legacy application.
- Involved in the technical incident resolution with prioritization and escalation by involving business, application, DBA, and ops teams.
- Resolved issues related to application code enhancements and deployments in the cloud, CI/CD pipelines, ELK logs, performa nce monitoring, and database querying.
- Collaborated with the development team to troubleshoot and resolve issues.
- Interacted and contributed my work with multiple teams in the flow dock collaboration tool.
- Enhanced the microservices code using 12 factors which had resolved the major production issue and thus satisfying business requirements.
- Responsible for maintaining and succeeding the pipeline jobs as green in Jenkins, microservices, Git/Subversion repositories, ELK and Cloud Foundry data centers, OpenStack instances.
- Collaborated with the architect to resolve the issues.
- Strengthened developmental methodologies and maintenance of process and associated scripts for automated build, testing, and deployment of applications to various environments.
- Deleted and created new pipelines for the applications that causing the issues.
- Written groovy and shell scripts for Jenkins jobs as a POC for the new implementation of jobs functionalities.
- Performed **Solr indexing** with verification on prod environment for syncing data from **DB2 to Solr**.
- Provided production support 24/7 using application performance management tool like app dynamics for all the business-critical applications by use of stack traces, transaction time, nodes health, etc.
- Worked on **SiteScope** alerts related to application production outages and provided **RCA** with **3L5Y**.

- Worked on **ELK** stack for the purpose of logs and maintained the **Kibana** instances when the space runs out by using **Linux** c ommands.
- Utilized **JFrog** artifactory to upload/download the build artifacts after a successful build.
- **Installed**, **configured**, and **administered** Jenkins and PCF dev on Linux machines in **OpenStack**.

9 FEB 2018 - 13 APR 2018 - West DesMoines, United States

Software Engineer

Softworld Technologies LLC

- Involved in all phases of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) like requirements gathering, analysis, design, developm ent, and deployment of various modules.
- Analyzed user requirements, procedures, and problems to aut omate processing or to improve existing computer systems.
- Interacted with the system/business analysts to understand the business requirement before translating into non-functional HT ML pages.
- Conferred with personnel organizational units involved to analyze current operational procedures, identify problems, and learn the specific output requirements.
- Documented detailed descriptions of users' needs to develop functional and technical specifications.
- Worked on Grafana, Prometheus, and exporters to monitor servers.
- Collaboration with teams and attending technical meetings for discussing application disaster recovery plans and deployme nt rollback plans.
- Use of computer/software technologies like Jenkins, Cloud Foundry, AngularJS, Dynatrace, HTML, CSS, ELK, Web UI design, Java/J2EE, and spring boot to provide solutions to user needs.
- Worked on microservices & their enhancements, NoSQL database, and SQL databases.
- Performed command-line execution of scripts, configurations, CRON jobs.
- Utilized **AppDynamics** to monitor application-level performance.
- Execution of the commands through Jenkins jobs on **Cloud foundry** environment.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

27 AUG 2016 – 5 DEC 2017 – 800 University Dr , Maryville, United States

Masters

Northwest Missouri State University

https://www.nwmissouri.edu/index.htm

16 AUG 2012 – 8 MAY 2016 – 66, Jntu Rd, Ashok Nagar, LIG, Kukatpally Housing Board Colony, Kukatpally, Hyderabad, Telangana, Hyderabad, India

Bachelors

JNTUH - Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University https://jntuh.ac.in/

LANGUAGE SKILLS

MOTHER TONGUE(S): Telugu

OTHER LANGUAGE(S):

English

Listening C2	Reading C2	Spoken production C2	Spoken interaction C2	Writing C2
Hindi				
Listening C2	Reading C2	Spoken production C2	Spoken interaction C2	Writing C2
German				
Listening A1	Reading A1	Spoken production A1	Spoken interaction A1	Writing A1

DIGITAL SKILLS

Cloud Tehnologies

Amazon Web Service (AWS) / Cloud Foundry / Microsoft Azure / Serve r4you / Open-Stack

CI-CD

Jenkins / TravisCl / GitHub Actions / GltLab

Configuration Management Tools

Terraform / Ansible

Log Monitoring Tools

Splunk / ELK (Elastic search, Logstash, Kibana)

Infra/Server Monitoring Tools

Zabbix / Grafana

Application Performance Monitoring Tools

App dynamics / Dynatrace APM

Webserver technologies

Web servers IIS Server Apache and NGINX / reverse proxying (Traefik)

Databases

WebLogic 12c / PostgreSQL / MongoDB, MySQL

Container Technologies

Kubernetes/Openshift / Docker engine & docker machine / Docker swarm / Portus / Docker / OpenShift / REX-Ray / Portainer

Programming Languages

Java / Groovy / Python / Go-Programming

Scripting Languages

Bash

Message Broakers

Apache kafka / Redis / RabbitMQ

Operating Systems

CentOS / Linux / Ubuntu / Microsoft Windows / Kali Linux

Miscellaneous

Confluence / Apache SOLR / Tableau / Visio / Maven / Stratos UI / Git / Filebeat / Slack / Prometheus / JSON / Microservices / Ji ra / Bare Metal

Services

Infrastructure as a Service (laaS) / Platform as a service (PaaS) / Functio n as a Service (FaaS) / OpenFaaS / Software as a Service (SaaS)

HONOURS AND AWARDS

4 OCT 2021

DevOps Deployment Automation with Terraform, AWS and

Docker – Udemy

Certification award in completion of my project of automating the production-grade deployment of dockerized applications in AWS using Terraform.

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-9fcc49bb-b6be-416c-a4dd-22e0bb1f77d0/

CREATIVE WORKS

27 JUN 2021 - CURRENT

Professional Blog

My Professional Blog provide details about my job experience, skills, CV, technical blogs, and more

https://shashankreddysunkara.github.io/CV/